<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Leftovers | Sunset Kitchen]]></title>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/categories/leftovers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-20T13:30:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jenn Vargas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pantry Grab Bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T23:16:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been craving a good, hearty sandwich lately. Growing up in New Jersey, sub sandwiches will always be close to my heart, but the whole vegetarian thing really throws a wrench into that gear. Since I moved away from home for college, the tradition has always been to pick up <a href="http://www.jerseymikes.com">Mike&rsquo;s Subs</a> for my first dinner at home &ndash; Ham and Provolone. No tomatoes, extra lettuce, light mayo, and all the seasonings. God I miss that sandwich.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;m trying to find a replacement. Tough going considering I&rsquo;m trying to avoid both crappy bread AND meat, but I thought I&rsquo;d give it a shot. Presenting, my &ldquo;whatever&rsquo;s in the pantry&rdquo; <del>sandwich</del> rollup:</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-19/IMG_6090-edited.jpg" alt="Grab Bag Sandwich" /></p>

<p>Appearance-wise: Not my best work, but let me tell you this thing was DELICIOUS. (Note to self: dig out the macro lens when you&rsquo;re not hungry). Today&rsquo;s version was leftovers from yesterday. I decided to add some sriracha to change it up a bit. Best. Decision. Ever.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s in it (note my very precise measures.):
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>1 can Chickpeas (drained and rinsed)</li>
<li>~5 walnuts</li>
<li>a handful of dried cranberries (not the sweetened with juice kind)</li>
<li>~4-5 baby carrots</li>
<li>2 scallions</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>~3 tbsp low fat mayo</li>
<li>~2 tbsp apple cider vinegar</li>
<li>~1 tbsp agave nectar</li>
<li>leaf of lettuce</li>
<li>whole grain tortilla</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s dead simple: Mash up the chickpeas a bit. I used a potato masher. Chop up all the remaining veggies (except the lettuce) and nuts into about equal sizes and add them to the chickpeas. In a separate bowl, mix together the mayo, vinegar, and agave. Pour it over the veggie mix and combine. Salt and pepper to taste.</p>

<p>Break up the lettuce on the tortilla to create a base for the veggie filling. Spoon out about 3-4 tablespoons depending on the size of your tortilla. Add some sriracha if that&rsquo;s your thing (and it should be). Wrap it up and enjoy!
</section></p>

<p>For good measure, I have a small cup of strawberries and pomegranate on the side. Strawberries and pomegranates make me happy.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t expecting to have so much in the way of leftovers after making this yesterday, but it turns out to produce about 3-4 servings which is amazing. Leftovers win.</p>

<p>If I had some tahini lying around I may have swapped it out with the mayo for a vegan option. I also may experiment with using greek yogurt instead of mayo, but that may be an experiment for when I&rsquo;m slightly more daring.</p>

<p>Hopefully from here forward my photo quality will improve. Live and learn.</p>

<p>Oh and PS I made a perfect soft boiled egg for the first time today. Nothing photo-worthy as it was just more leftovers, but I&rsquo;ll definitely be making it again so stay tuned for that one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
