<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Sunset Kitchen]]></title>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T18:54:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jenn Vargas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/thanksgiving/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T08:19:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/thanksgiving</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hope everyone had a great Thanksgiving!</p>

<p>This year, I had the crazy idea to host Thanksgiving in my apartment. For the past few years it&rsquo;s just been my mom and me for Thanksgiving and I thought it was time to change things up. I love the idea of a big Thanksgiving &ndash; lots of people: friends, family, new friends, tons of food. The biggest Thanksgiving I can remember growing up was maybe around 6 people.</p>

<p>Timing was perfect, really. My kitchen actually has full-sized appliances. I have an incredibly flexible work schedule, meaning I could make quick trips to the grocery store and start prep days in advance. I have a new-found love of cooking and entertaining. And I&rsquo;m walking distance away from the start of the Macy&rsquo;s Thanksgiving Day Parade. All signs were pointing to an NYC Thanksgiving.</p>

<p>So I convinced my mom that we should have a Friendsgiving. She could come up and cook the turkey in my apartment, and we could go to the parade this year instead of watching it on TV. Oh yeah, and there would be a new Snoopy balloon. I think that sealed the deal.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/foreverdigital/11138245453" title="Snoopy by Jenn Vargas, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5490/11138245453_31ffa26057_k.jpg" width="2048" height="1536" alt="Snoopy balloon"></a></p>

<p>I sent out invitations around the beginning of the month and to my surprise and excitement, Thanksgiving was going to be a group of 10 people. That&rsquo;s where the fun began. I had to figure out how to seat 10 people for Thanksgiving dinner in my apartment. I had it set in my mind that dinner needed to be seated at a table. Not formal, but not sitting around the living room with plates on laps. I wanted it to feel like a special occasion. While that might not sound like a huge barrier, when you live in an apartment in NYC, odds are high that you eat most of your meals on the couch from a take-out container. We don&rsquo;t have a dining room table or anything that even resembles one.</p>

<p>Piecing together borrowed tables and chairs, we managed to figure out how to seat 10 people pretty comfortably. Miracles happen.</p>

<p>At some point during all of the prep work on Wednesday night I forgot to stop to take pictures, so documentation is sparse, but I did manage to get ONE moderately-clear photo of the the festivities:</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-12-02/thanksgiving.jpg" alt="Friendsgiving" /></p>

<p>Food-wise, it was a bit insane. We had SO MUCH FOOD. We made the turkey, stuffing, mashed potatoes (of the regular and sweet variety), biscuits, corn, cranberry sauce, and green beans. Everyone contributed something else from cheese and wine to proscuitto-wrapped dates to crazy addictive homemade apple cider caramels. By the time dessert rolled along we were basically comatose, but in the best kind of way.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be posting the recipes I put together over the next couple of days. Today I&rsquo;ll start with the simplest one that you can start days in advance: Compound butter. This was my first time making compound butter. Turns out it&rsquo;s dead simple and I&rsquo;m now obsessed.</p>

<p><section class="recipe">
For Thanksgiving I decided to go with 2 butters: a sweet, dessert-like butter and then something a bit more savory that would complement the meal. I settled on a Cranberry Cinnamon and Black Pepper Honey.</p>

<p><strong>Cranberry Cinnamon Compound Butter</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1 stick unsalted butter, room temperature</li>
<li>~&frac14; cup of chopped dried cranberries</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp cinnamon (give or take depending on your taste)</li>
<li>~1 tsp honey</li>
<li>tiny pinch of salt</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Black Pepper Honey Compound Butter</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1 stick unsalted butter, room temperature</li>
<li>~1 tbsp cracked black pepper</li>
<li>~1 tbsp honey</li>
<li>tiny pinch of salt</li>
</ul>


<p>Once your butter is room temp, use a wooden spoon (or some other strong mixing implement) to mix in the other ingredients. Be sure to squish the butter a lot with the spoon to eliminate solid chunks of butter and so all of the ingredients are blended throughout. It&rsquo;s especially easy to tell when you&rsquo;re fully mixed with the Cranberry Cinnamon because it takes on a reddish color &ndash; the unmixed bits will stand out.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-12-02/compoundbutter.jpg" alt="Compound Butter - Sunset Kitchen" /></p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re satisfied with your mixture, tear a small piece of wax paper and place your butter on it in a log shape. Roll it up like a piece of hard candy and place it in the refrigerator to harden again. If you&rsquo;re making smaller amounts, you could also consider storing it in an 8oz mason jar which you could serve it right out of.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-12-02/compoundbutterlog.jpg" alt="Compound Butter - Sunset Kitchen" />
</section></p>

<p>The Cranberry Cinnamon turned out to be my favorite &ndash; especially spread on a warm biscuit.</p>

<p>The next compound butter I want to experiment with is cilantro lime. I love cilantro anything. I also want to do some experimenting before Christmas so I konw which one I want to make for the day!</p>

<p>Coming up: Apple Cider Sangria (SO GOOD), Sugared Cranberries, and Roasted Green Beans. Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coconut Red Lentil Soup]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/coconut-red-lentil-soup/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-27T09:40:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/coconut-red-lentil-soup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s crazy to me that I didn&rsquo;t even try Indian food until sometime during the second half of college because it now ranks up there with some of my all-time favorite flavors. I think it&rsquo;s the combination of savory, spicy, and cilantro that just always gets me. Actually, anything with cilantro is great in my book.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always shied away from cooking Indian food at home &ndash; mostly because it always sounded so complicated with the multitude of spices. And, if I&rsquo;m being honest, I really didn&rsquo;t want my whole apartment to smell like curry. I don&rsquo;t like lingering food scents, especially when they get on my clothes. Unless that scent is chocolate chip cookies, of course.</p>

<p>Continuing on my cooking adventures, I&rsquo;ve really been craving a soup. Originally I thought I wanted to make something broth-based, but I couldn&rsquo;t find anything that felt stick-to-your-ribs enough for my craving. Instead, I found this great recipe for <a href="http://www.101cookbooks.com/archives/coconut-red-lentil-soup-recipe.html">Coconut Red Lentil Soup</a> on another new favorite blog of mine: <a href="http://www.101cookbooks.com">101 Cookbooks</a>.</p>

<p>We were working out of my apartment so Kate and her boyfriend Mat were going to join me for dinner. I was working and cooking at the same time (thank god for the passthru window in my kitchen) and had a bunch of things running through my head at once. I&rsquo;d set out a stick of butter to do a practice run of <a href="http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-cheese-gougres-169039">gougeres</a> for Thanksgiving, and in my multitasking I actually used that whole stick of butter in this recipe instead of the measely 2 tbsp it called for.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-25/coconut-red-lentil-soup.jpg" alt="Coconut Red Lentil Soup" /></p>

<p>Artery-clogging overuse of butter aside, this soup was FAN.TAS.TIC. I mean, so good that Kate may or may not have stood over the stove and sopped up every last bit of soup from the ladle with the gougere.</p>

<p>I used the recipe from 101 cookbooks pretty much wholesale, so I won&rsquo;t replicate it here. I will say that I found the cooking time to be a bit short. I ended up simmering the soup down for at least another 10-15 minutes to get it to the consistency I like. It was far too watery for my taste at the 20 minute simmer time suggested in the receipe.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-25/gougere.jpg" alt="Cheddar Gougere" /></p>

<p>The gougeres made a decent crouton for the soup, but I think next time I&rsquo;d like something more along the lines of a garlic toast. The recipe is straight from The Kitchn. I skipped the mustard powder as I didn&rsquo;t have any on-hand. This is definitely a great foundational recipe for mixing in different ingredients, etc. I&rsquo;ll be experimenting with it more in the future. And I&rsquo;m glad I did a test-run before Thanksgiving as I&rsquo;ll probably need to double or triple the recipe for that. The measurements given yield about 16 gougeres. I baked up about 6 and put the rest in freezer for a rainy day.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m noticing that I&rsquo;m finding myself in a bit of a predicament lately. Since I&rsquo;ve been focusing so much on cooking proper meals, when I do want to just have a day of no-cooking, there are usually some really great leftovers around! I do find myself occasionally craving something more snacky, so I think I&rsquo;m going to have to keep my old standby of apples and almond butter around for safe measure. It&rsquo;s kind of nice to be able to go to the kitchen and pull out some leftover quinoa salad and throw an egg on top to freshen it up or have lots of really different toppings around to spice up my morning yogurt.</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;m getting used to this.</p>

<p>And on that note, Sunset Kitchen will be taking a brief pause to cook up a storm for Thanksgiving. As it&rsquo;s the first Thanksgiving I&rsquo;m hosting, I&rsquo;ll be sure to do a recap post after. It&rsquo;ll also give me a great excuse to figure out interesting things to do with the leftovers (if there are any)!</p>

<p>Until next week &ndash; Happy Thanksgiving!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn Quinoa Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/autumn-quinoa-salad/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T08:48:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/autumn-quinoa-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Autumn is the best time of the year &ndash; leaves change, food gets warmer and heartier, summer heatwaves finally let up, and snow is just around the corner. This year, though, I&rsquo;m seeing Fall through a whole new lens: DELICIOUSNESS.</p>

<p>Up until now, most autumn veggies were not on my list of edible foods. Brussels sprouts, squash, cauliflower were avoided like the plague. That&rsquo;s all changed thanks to a few friends who were insistant that I develop a less picky approach to food and I couldn&rsquo;t be happier. Autumn foods are amazing and it&rsquo;s giving me a whole new range of options for cooking.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s lunch was an Autumn Quinoa Salad that I pieced together using various things I had around the kitchen.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-final.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl" /></p>

<p>I mentioned my <a href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/sweet-potato-soldiers-plus-soft-boiled-eggs/">new-found love of roasting</a> the other day, and this bowl definitely builds on that. And it turned out to be my fluffiest quinoa yet. We&rsquo;re making progress! Here&rsquo;s the breakdown:
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>&frac12; cup regular white quinoa</li>
<li>&frac12; cup red quinoa</li>
<li>2 tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>1.5 cups water</li>
<li>1 large sweet potato, peeled + cubed</li>
<li>&frac12; butternut squash, seeded + cubed</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp cumin</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp cinnamon</li>
<li>~1 tsp each salt + pepper</li>
<li>&frac12; cup dried unsweetened cranberries, chopped</li>
<li>&frac12; cup pecans, chopped</li>
<li>1 cup chilled pomegranate arils</li>
<li>1.5 cups arugula</li>
<li>~1.5 tbsp fresh lemon juice</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-veggies.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Roasted Butternut Squash and Sweet Potato" />
<strong>For the roasted veggies</strong></p>

<p>This is so simple: Preheat the oven to 400ยบ. Toss your chopped squash and sweet potato in about a tablespoon or so of olive oil, adding in about a teaspoon each of salt and pepper. I also added in a bit of cumin and cinnamon to make it a bit more interesting. Once everything is thoroughly coated, spread it out on a cookie sheet lined with parchment paper. Loosely cover in foil &ndash; just lay a sheet over it, no need to secure it to the edges or anything. It&rsquo;s mostly to prevent the veggies from browning too quickly before they cook through the insides. Roast the veggies with foil over them for about 15-20 minutes until they&rsquo;re soft. Then remove the foil and leave them in for another 5-10 minutes to get a little crispy on the outsides. You want them to be soft, but with a little color. Remove them from the heat and set aside to cool.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-quinoa.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Fluffy Mixed Quinoa" />
<strong>For the quinoa</strong></p>

<p>While the veggies are roasting in the oven:</p>

<p>Rinse the quinoa thoroughly. Add about a tablespoon of olive oil into your pot and add the quinoa, stirring to coat the quinoa with the olive oil. Heat the olive oil and quinoa over medium heat, stirring for a bit to make sure nothing sticks. The goal here is to suck out the moisture from the quinoa so it&rsquo;ll better-absorb the water you&rsquo;re about to boil it in. Once the quinoa starts to sound a little crackle-y, time to add the water and a pinch of salt. Pour 1.5 cups of water over the quinoa and bring it to a boil. Once it&rsquo;s boiling, lower the heat and put a lid on it. Let it do its thing for about 15 minutes until the water is absorbed (You might want to stir it around a bit toward the end to make sure it doesn&rsquo;t stick to the bottom of the pot.)</p>

<p>When it&rsquo;s done, add it to a large bowl where you&rsquo;ll assemble your salad. Leave it to cool a bit.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-toppings.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Chopped Pecans + Dried Cranberries" />
<strong>For the toppings</strong></p>

<p>While the veggies and quinoa are on auto-pilot, time to chop up your toppings. Just run a rough chop through both the pecans and cranberries.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-mixed.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - The Gang's All Here" />
<strong>Putting it all together</strong></p>

<p>Once everything is warm to the touch, add your cranberries, pecans, and pomegranate to the quinoa. Mix them through for an even distribution. Then add in your roasted veggies and gently mix them through. Adding them separately lets them keep their shape a bit more than the potential mashing they could get when you&rsquo;re mixing the more solid ingredients. I added in the arugula last so it didn&rsquo;t wilt. Squeeze some lemon juice over the top and salt and pepper to taste.</p>

<p><em>Makes 6 servings.</em>
</section></p>

<p>You&rsquo;re all done! Go forth and enjoy!</p>

<p>Kate was over so there weren&rsquo;t a ton of leftovers (we both unabashedly went back for seconds), but the next time I make this I may use my leftovers for breakfast and throw a poached or soft-boiled egg on top.</p>

<p>As an exercise to prove (or perhaps disprove) that cooking at home is cheaper than ordering out, I did a bit of a cost breakdown for this dish. I had everything on-hand, so that was nice, but I estimate that this cost about $12 in ingredients. Divide that by the 6 servings it got us, that works out to be $2/serving which is wayyyyyy less than you would pay for takeout. Success.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh My Chai.]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/oh-my-chai/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-25T09:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/oh-my-chai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My love affair with Chai began sometime during college and peaked my senior year when I, along with the other editors of the newspaper, would gather in one of the library cafes between classes and hang out. I would grab a chai when I got there and then another on my way out to my Anthro class where it was the only thing that kept me awake / entertained. Even in the middle of an Ithaca winter, I loved my iced soy chai.</p>

<p>After college, I could never find a place that made chai the way I got it at that library. Nearly 3 years of searching to no avail and I finally gave up. I would only get chai when I returned to campus for visits here and there.</p>

<p>Recently, though, my friend/business partner <a href="http://twitter.com/katekendall">Kate</a> re-lit my chai cravings. She&rsquo;s obsessed with chai lattes. In fact, if you&rsquo;re looking for her, you can probably find her in a Starbucks ordering one. Or two.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been working out of our apartments lately and Kate&rsquo;s usually at my apartment at least a few times a week, Starbucks chai in hand. I envied her chais. I missed my Libe Cafe chais. Starbucks chai just doesn&rsquo;t do it for me. Short of taking a 5-hour bus ride up to Ithaca, I thought I was out of luck.</p>

<p>Then fate stepped in, and in my endless browsing of Pinterest, I stumbled across a chai latte recipe. Made from scratch. And it was a concentrate that you could then add milk and ice to. All the makings of my beloved Libe Cafe chai.</p>

<p>I had to make it. And I knew Kate would be game for at least trying it. It&rsquo;s way more fun to make things for other people than for myself.</p>

<p>It felt like I was buying nearly the entire spice section at Fairway. Things I didn&rsquo;t really know existed like caramom pods made their way into my basket. God spices are pricey.</p>

<p>I was beyond excited to try this recipe and I knew Kate would be coming over, so I dove right in and let me tell you: SPOT. ON. I can die happy now. It kind of makes me want to go sit in my Antro class and pretend to listen while really checking Twitter and IMing my friends who were sitting next to me. So. Good.</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-21/chai-brewing.jpg" alt="DIY Iced Chai Latte - Everybody in the pool!" /></p>

<p>The recipe is from one of my new favorite blogs: <a href="http://www.biggirlssmallkitchen.com/2011/06/working-with-what-you-have-iced-chai-tea-latte.html">Big Girls, Small Kitchen</a>. I followed it almost exactly but replaced the honey with agave nectar (only because I&rsquo;m running low on honey) and used almond milk. Next time I might cook it down a bit more since it wasn&rsquo;t quite concentrated enough and the 6 tablespoons of chai : 1 cup of milk tasted mostly like milk. I ended up with almost a 1:1 ratio of chai to milk.</p>

<p>The good news is I doubled the recipe to make 2 batches, so even though the chai won&rsquo;t produce as many servings as I thought it would, I don&rsquo;t have to go back and make more immediately!</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-21/chai-steam.jpg" alt="DIY Chai == Happiness" /></p>

<p>I prefer my chai iced, but Kate&rsquo;s was hot: just added some vanilla almond milk to the syrup on the stovetop. Her verdict: &ldquo;Best chai ever.&rdquo; I&rsquo;ll take it.</p>

<p>This winter just got so much better. And it turns out it goes wonderfully with my <a href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/lessons-learned-not-so-chocolate-chip-cookies">&ldquo;tea cookies&rdquo;</a>. A win all around.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunset Kitchen?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/sunset-kitchen/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T10:08:59-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/sunset-kitchen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I started this blog it was under a different name. In fact, I&rsquo;d already published my first post when I had a bit of an epiphany and checked to see if the name sunsetkitchen.com was registed. Surprisingly, it wasn&rsquo;t. I immediately bought it and knew it was the perfect name for this blog.</p>

<p>My kitchen has phenomenal sunset view. I post pictures of it to my facebook/<a href="http://instagram.com/jennjenn">instagram</a> all the time and occasionally people come by <em>just</em> to see the sunset. &ldquo;It really never gets old.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve lived here for nearly a year now and even now, when I notice the light starting to change, I run to the kitchen window to check out the sunset. Some days are better than others, but it&rsquo;s always a sight to see. It&rsquo;s not uncommon for me to literally hang out of my living room window (on the 24th floor) to get the perfect angle for a photo on a weekly basis.</p>

<p>When I mentioned the name of the blog to <a href="http://twitter.com/katekendall">Kate</a>, she gave me the great idea of adding a sunset photo to every post. I figured that be a bit overload considering the sunset doesn&rsquo;t change <em>that</em> much from day-to-day, so for now, a weekly sunset photo might do the trick.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had some spectacular ones this week, but I thought I&rsquo;d start with the sunset that inspired the color palette for this blog, taken just last week:</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-21/original-sunset.jpg" alt="The sunset that inspired it all" /></p>

<p>Completely unedited. The colors were just phenomenal. It&rsquo;s amazing to watch the sunset change over the course of the year and with different weather patterns. Hopefully you&rsquo;ll enjoy the view too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lessons Learned: (Not So) Chocolate Chip Oatmeal Cookies]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/lessons-learned-not-so-chocolate-chip-cookies/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T08:24:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/lessons-learned-not-so-chocolate-chip-cookies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not all of my cooking adventures result in success. Last night&rsquo;s endeavor was one of those valiant, but failed efforts.</p>

<p>I had a chocolate chip cookie craving. Well, more accurately, I had some chocolate chips in my pantry and I wanted an excuse to use them. After a quick run to the store for butter (Can you believe I didn&rsquo;t have any butter? I haven&rsquo;t used it in almost a year!), I grabbed my hand mixer and started to measure out ingredients.</p>

<p>Then I realized I didn&rsquo;t have brown sugar. Oops. Not wanting to go BACK to the store I decided to substitute regular granulated sugar. Mistake #1.</p>

<p>Then I thought: hey, let me spice these up! I love chocolate chip cookies with nuts and I have some walnuts in the pantry. Yes. Oh and I have some cranberries. I like cranberries. Oh! And shaved coconut! I love coconut cookies. Into the dough it all went.</p>

<p>As I started to scoop the dough onto the cookie sheets I realized the consistency wasn&rsquo;t quite right, but I thought maybe this is what homemade-without-the-help-of-Pillsbury cookies looked like. I pressed on.</p>

<p>First batch into the oven, I noticed that they weren&rsquo;t browning. I&rsquo;m guessing that&rsquo;s where the brown sugar would have come into play. These are some of the beigest chocolate chip cookies I&rsquo;ve ever encountered.</p>

<p>They were also some of the driest chocolate chip cookies I&rsquo;ve ever encountered. Bordering on biscotti consistency. Not quite right. I&rsquo;ve decided to spin it as &ldquo;Look! I made tea cookies!&rdquo; because I&rsquo;m pretty sure they&rsquo;ll be delicious with my morning tea. Soft, gooey chocolate chip cookies they were not. Sad.</p>

<p>Just for the sake of documentation, here&rsquo;s what was in them:</p>

<ul>
<li>1 &frac12; cups of quaker oats</li>
<li>&frac34; cup of flour</li>
<li>&frac34; cup of granulated sugar</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon of baking soda</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon of baking powder</li>
<li>&frac12; teaspoon of cinnamon</li>
<li>pinch of salt</li>
<li>&frac12; cup of unsalted butter, softened</li>
<li>1 cup of tollhouse chocolate chip morsels</li>
<li>&frac14; cup of shaved coconut</li>
<li>1/8 cup of chopped walnuts</li>
<li>1/8 cup of chopped dried cranberries</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-20/cookiedough.jpg" alt="I should have known. I'll spare you the finished product photo. It looks just like this, but drier." /></p>

<h2>Lessons Learned</h2>

<ul>
<li>Keep brown sugar around at all times. And no, granulated sugar is not an adequate substitute.</li>
<li>Get normal sized chocolate chips. I&rsquo;m not a huge fan of super-chocolately cookies so I thought these would be a great alternative. The lack of melted chocolate definitely contributed to the dryness.</li>
<li>Get some parchment paper. They burned on the bottoms too easily and I couldn&rsquo;t get them off of the cookie nicely, despite greasing it.</li>
<li>Perhaps add some apple sauce to the mix for moisture. Adding more dry ingredients without adding more wet ingredients was definitely a dumb move.</li>
</ul>


<p>Not a total loss. They&rsquo;re still pretty delicious and I&rsquo;m hoping that they&rsquo;ll taste even better with a cup of tea.</p>

<p>Ah well. I&rsquo;ll try again soon. The night wasn&rsquo;t a total loss. I made some awesome chai from scratch. But that&rsquo;s a story for another day :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet Potato Soldiers + Soft Boiled Eggs]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/sweet-potato-soldiers-plus-soft-boiled-eggs/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T13:06:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/sweet-potato-soldiers-plus-soft-boiled-eggs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Soft-boiled eggs are a bit of a new discovery for me. I mean, I knew they existed, but I never really tried them. I practically lived on hard-boiled eggs for a few months &ndash; I ate them every morning for breakfast after becoming a vegetarian and realizing I was severely lacking in protein intake. (Sans yolk. So gross.)</p>

<p>While watching Master Chef Junior a few weeks ago, I was totally taken by the soft-boiled egg challenge. They looked so tasty! After some research, I boiled my water, set my timer for 5 minutes, plunked my egg in, and crossed my fingers.</p>

<p>Magcially, the egg came out PERFECTLY. I&rsquo;m now a soft-boiled egg convert. It has all of the yolky goodness of my favorite Sunday-at-home breakfast (eggs sunny side up and an english muffin), but isn&rsquo;t as easy to screw up or under-cook as a sunny-side up egg. Amazing.</p>

<p>Another new discovery is the wonder of roasting veggies. They&rsquo;re so versatile and yummy. I bought 2 sweet potatoes at Trader Joe&rsquo;s the other day, not quite knowing what I&rsquo;d do with them, but they were cheap and I&rsquo;d figure it out later. I landed on sweet potato fries: roasted veggies in fast-food form!</p>

<p>My craving for soft boiled eggs and the two sweet potatoes sitting on my counter, haunting me, led me to this:</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-20/sweetpotatosoldiers.jpg" alt="Soft-boiled Eggs and Spicy Sweet Potato Soldiers" /></p>

<p>So. Good. And filling. I wanted to try something a little more than throwing the sweet potatoes in the oven with some salt and pepper, so I settled on making them sweet and spicy.
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>2 medium sweet potatoes</li>
<li>~2 tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>good pinch of salt</li>
<li>bunch of ground black pepper</li>
<li>about a tablespoon of red pepper flakes (depending on how spicy you want them)</li>
</ul>


<p>Preheat the oven to 400ยบ. Cut your sweet potatoes into fries (or wedges!), throw them in a bowl, pour all of the seasonings &amp; olive oil on top and mix it all up. Spread it onto a cookie sheet (lined with parchment paper or a silpat to keep it all loose) and plunk them in the oven for 25-30 minutes.</p>

<p>When they&rsquo;re soft and have a little bit of brown to them, take them out and put them on a paper towel-lined plate to catch any rogue drops of olive oil.</p>

<p>While they&rsquo;re cooling a bit, time to boil up your water and put in your egg. Set your iPhone timer (it&rsquo;s a wonderful thing) to 5 minutes. Remove, cool SLIGHTLY (not too long or the egg will continue to cook), and peel.
</section></p>

<p>I managed to break the egg as I was peeling it so I sliced it in the middle, but ideally it would have been a slice off of the top so it could act more like a dipping cup. In this form it was a lot easier to roughly cut up the egg and eat it all together with a fork.</p>

<p>I could see this being a great brunch dish for a few people (soft-boiled eggs are too tempermental for a large group, I think), but for now it&rsquo;ll stick around as a great way to spice up leftover roasted veggies!</p>

<p>Next up: attempting to master the fried egg. Tricky sucker.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pantry Grab Bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T23:16:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been craving a good, hearty sandwich lately. Growing up in New Jersey, sub sandwiches will always be close to my heart, but the whole vegetarian thing really throws a wrench into that gear. Since I moved away from home for college, the tradition has always been to pick up <a href="http://www.jerseymikes.com">Mike&rsquo;s Subs</a> for my first dinner at home &ndash; Ham and Provolone. No tomatoes, extra lettuce, light mayo, and all the seasonings. God I miss that sandwich.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;m trying to find a replacement. Tough going considering I&rsquo;m trying to avoid both crappy bread AND meat, but I thought I&rsquo;d give it a shot. Presenting, my &ldquo;whatever&rsquo;s in the pantry&rdquo; <del>sandwich</del> rollup:</p>

<p><img src="http://sunsetkitchen.com/uploads/2013-11-19/IMG_6090-edited.jpg" alt="Grab Bag Sandwich" /></p>

<p>Appearance-wise: Not my best work, but let me tell you this thing was DELICIOUS. (Note to self: dig out the macro lens when you&rsquo;re not hungry). Today&rsquo;s version was leftovers from yesterday. I decided to add some sriracha to change it up a bit. Best. Decision. Ever.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s in it (note my very precise measures.):
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>1 can Chickpeas (drained and rinsed)</li>
<li>~5 walnuts</li>
<li>a handful of dried cranberries (not the sweetened with juice kind)</li>
<li>~4-5 baby carrots</li>
<li>2 scallions</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>~3 tbsp low fat mayo</li>
<li>~2 tbsp apple cider vinegar</li>
<li>~1 tbsp agave nectar</li>
<li>leaf of lettuce</li>
<li>whole grain tortilla</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s dead simple: Mash up the chickpeas a bit. I used a potato masher. Chop up all the remaining veggies (except the lettuce) and nuts into about equal sizes and add them to the chickpeas. In a separate bowl, mix together the mayo, vinegar, and agave. Pour it over the veggie mix and combine. Salt and pepper to taste.</p>

<p>Break up the lettuce on the tortilla to create a base for the veggie filling. Spoon out about 3-4 tablespoons depending on the size of your tortilla. Add some sriracha if that&rsquo;s your thing (and it should be). Wrap it up and enjoy!
</section></p>

<p>For good measure, I have a small cup of strawberries and pomegranate on the side. Strawberries and pomegranates make me happy.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t expecting to have so much in the way of leftovers after making this yesterday, but it turns out to produce about 3-4 servings which is amazing. Leftovers win.</p>

<p>If I had some tahini lying around I may have swapped it out with the mayo for a vegan option. I also may experiment with using greek yogurt instead of mayo, but that may be an experiment for when I&rsquo;m slightly more daring.</p>

<p>Hopefully from here forward my photo quality will improve. Live and learn.</p>

<p>Oh and PS I made a perfect soft boiled egg for the first time today. Nothing photo-worthy as it was just more leftovers, but I&rsquo;ll definitely be making it again so stay tuned for that one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Change of Heart]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/a-change-of-heart/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T15:26:53-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/a-change-of-heart</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a twenty-something living in New York City, I held fast to the belief that eating out was way more cost-effective than attempting to do any sort of cooking at home. I&rsquo;d generally eat a big lunch at work and then come home to snack on something for dinner. I&rsquo;ve often been reprimanded by friends for subsisting entirely on Cheerios or chips + salsa. These always seemed like reasonable dinners to me. I&rsquo;m fairly certain that I didn&rsquo;t even turn on the stove in my apartment until at least 8 months of living here.</p>

<p>Things started to change when I joined the gym and found myself starving when I got home. Cheerios, chips, and salsa just weren&rsquo;t cutting it for dinner anymore. I upped my game by adding smoothies to my repertoire. Slowly but surely, I starting buying fruits and veggies to keep chopped up in the fridge and learned the magic of meal prep.</p>

<p>The icing on the cake was when I decided to try a vegetarian diet. It opened a whole new world of veggies to me &ndash; the likes of brussels sprouts and broccoli &ndash; and also made me realize that these things weren&rsquo;t that expensive in the grocery store and were a lot less hassle than going out to eat where the only vegetarian option was something like pasta or a boring salad.</p>

<p>I started to cook. And bake. And I loved it.</p>

<p>Lately I cook nearly every meal. I&rsquo;ve even adopted a rule regarding junk food: if I make it myself from scratch, it&rsquo;s OK to eat it (within reason of course). No buying cookies or ice cream at Fairway &ndash; I&rsquo;ve found simple substitutes to make all of these things myself by keeping a few ingredients on hand.</p>

<p>So that&rsquo;s what this is about. I love making things that I can share with other people. From websites to dinner parties, making things that others enjoy is one of my greatest sources of happiness and satisfaction. And since I can&rsquo;t throw a dinner party every night (as much as I&rsquo;d love to), I thought I&rsquo;d start to document my adventures here.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;ll be a mix of experiments, learning, recipes, thoughts, and who knows what. I just know that I want to make delicious, mostly healthy food, and share it with great people. Thanks for being one of those great people. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
