<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vegetarian | Sunset Kitchen]]></title>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/categories/vegetarian/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T18:54:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jenn Vargas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn Quinoa Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/autumn-quinoa-salad/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T08:48:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/autumn-quinoa-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Autumn is the best time of the year &ndash; leaves change, food gets warmer and heartier, summer heatwaves finally let up, and snow is just around the corner. This year, though, I&rsquo;m seeing Fall through a whole new lens: DELICIOUSNESS.</p>

<p>Up until now, most autumn veggies were not on my list of edible foods. Brussels sprouts, squash, cauliflower were avoided like the plague. That&rsquo;s all changed thanks to a few friends who were insistant that I develop a less picky approach to food and I couldn&rsquo;t be happier. Autumn foods are amazing and it&rsquo;s giving me a whole new range of options for cooking.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s lunch was an Autumn Quinoa Salad that I pieced together using various things I had around the kitchen.</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-final.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl" /></p>

<p>I mentioned my <a href="/sweet-potato-soldiers-plus-soft-boiled-eggs/">new-found love of roasting</a> the other day, and this bowl definitely builds on that. And it turned out to be my fluffiest quinoa yet. We&rsquo;re making progress! Here&rsquo;s the breakdown:
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>&frac12; cup regular white quinoa</li>
<li>&frac12; cup red quinoa</li>
<li>2 tbsp olive oil</li>
<li>1.5 cups water</li>
<li>1 large sweet potato, peeled + cubed</li>
<li>&frac12; butternut squash, seeded + cubed</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp cumin</li>
<li>&frac14; tsp cinnamon</li>
<li>~1 tsp each salt + pepper</li>
<li>&frac12; cup dried unsweetened cranberries, chopped</li>
<li>&frac12; cup pecans, chopped</li>
<li>1 cup chilled pomegranate arils</li>
<li>1.5 cups arugula</li>
<li>~1.5 tbsp fresh lemon juice</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-veggies.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Roasted Butternut Squash and Sweet Potato" />
<strong>For the roasted veggies</strong></p>

<p>This is so simple: Preheat the oven to 400ยบ. Toss your chopped squash and sweet potato in about a tablespoon or so of olive oil, adding in about a teaspoon each of salt and pepper. I also added in a bit of cumin and cinnamon to make it a bit more interesting. Once everything is thoroughly coated, spread it out on a cookie sheet lined with parchment paper. Loosely cover in foil &ndash; just lay a sheet over it, no need to secure it to the edges or anything. It&rsquo;s mostly to prevent the veggies from browning too quickly before they cook through the insides. Roast the veggies with foil over them for about 15-20 minutes until they&rsquo;re soft. Then remove the foil and leave them in for another 5-10 minutes to get a little crispy on the outsides. You want them to be soft, but with a little color. Remove them from the heat and set aside to cool.</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-quinoa.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Fluffy Mixed Quinoa" />
<strong>For the quinoa</strong></p>

<p>While the veggies are roasting in the oven:</p>

<p>Rinse the quinoa thoroughly. Add about a tablespoon of olive oil into your pot and add the quinoa, stirring to coat the quinoa with the olive oil. Heat the olive oil and quinoa over medium heat, stirring for a bit to make sure nothing sticks. The goal here is to suck out the moisture from the quinoa so it&rsquo;ll better-absorb the water you&rsquo;re about to boil it in. Once the quinoa starts to sound a little crackle-y, time to add the water and a pinch of salt. Pour 1.5 cups of water over the quinoa and bring it to a boil. Once it&rsquo;s boiling, lower the heat and put a lid on it. Let it do its thing for about 15 minutes until the water is absorbed (You might want to stir it around a bit toward the end to make sure it doesn&rsquo;t stick to the bottom of the pot.)</p>

<p>When it&rsquo;s done, add it to a large bowl where you&rsquo;ll assemble your salad. Leave it to cool a bit.</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-toppings.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - Chopped Pecans + Dried Cranberries" />
<strong>For the toppings</strong></p>

<p>While the veggies and quinoa are on auto-pilot, time to chop up your toppings. Just run a rough chop through both the pecans and cranberries.</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-22/quinoa-bowl-mixed.jpg" alt="Autumn Quinoa Bowl - The Gang's All Here" />
<strong>Putting it all together</strong></p>

<p>Once everything is warm to the touch, add your cranberries, pecans, and pomegranate to the quinoa. Mix them through for an even distribution. Then add in your roasted veggies and gently mix them through. Adding them separately lets them keep their shape a bit more than the potential mashing they could get when you&rsquo;re mixing the more solid ingredients. I added in the arugula last so it didn&rsquo;t wilt. Squeeze some lemon juice over the top and salt and pepper to taste.</p>

<p><em>Makes 6 servings.</em>
</section></p>

<p>You&rsquo;re all done! Go forth and enjoy!</p>

<p>Kate was over so there weren&rsquo;t a ton of leftovers (we both unabashedly went back for seconds), but the next time I make this I may use my leftovers for breakfast and throw a poached or soft-boiled egg on top.</p>

<p>As an exercise to prove (or perhaps disprove) that cooking at home is cheaper than ordering out, I did a bit of a cost breakdown for this dish. I had everything on-hand, so that was nice, but I estimate that this cost about $12 in ingredients. Divide that by the 6 servings it got us, that works out to be $2/serving which is wayyyyyy less than you would pay for takeout. Success.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pantry Grab Bag]]></title>
    <link href="http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T23:16:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sunsetkitchen.com/pantry-grab-bag</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been craving a good, hearty sandwich lately. Growing up in New Jersey, sub sandwiches will always be close to my heart, but the whole vegetarian thing really throws a wrench into that gear. Since I moved away from home for college, the tradition has always been to pick up <a href="http://www.jerseymikes.com">Mike&rsquo;s Subs</a> for my first dinner at home &ndash; Ham and Provolone. No tomatoes, extra lettuce, light mayo, and all the seasonings. God I miss that sandwich.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;m trying to find a replacement. Tough going considering I&rsquo;m trying to avoid both crappy bread AND meat, but I thought I&rsquo;d give it a shot. Presenting, my &ldquo;whatever&rsquo;s in the pantry&rdquo; <del>sandwich</del> rollup:</p>

<p><img src="/uploads/2013-11-19/IMG_6090-edited.jpg" alt="Grab Bag Sandwich" /></p>

<p>Appearance-wise: Not my best work, but let me tell you this thing was DELICIOUS. (Note to self: dig out the macro lens when you&rsquo;re not hungry). Today&rsquo;s version was leftovers from yesterday. I decided to add some sriracha to change it up a bit. Best. Decision. Ever.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s in it (note my very precise measures.):
<section class="recipe"></p>

<ul>
<li>1 can Chickpeas (drained and rinsed)</li>
<li>~5 walnuts</li>
<li>a handful of dried cranberries (not the sweetened with juice kind)</li>
<li>~4-5 baby carrots</li>
<li>2 scallions</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>~3 tbsp low fat mayo</li>
<li>~2 tbsp apple cider vinegar</li>
<li>~1 tbsp agave nectar</li>
<li>leaf of lettuce</li>
<li>whole grain tortilla</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s dead simple: Mash up the chickpeas a bit. I used a potato masher. Chop up all the remaining veggies (except the lettuce) and nuts into about equal sizes and add them to the chickpeas. In a separate bowl, mix together the mayo, vinegar, and agave. Pour it over the veggie mix and combine. Salt and pepper to taste.</p>

<p>Break up the lettuce on the tortilla to create a base for the veggie filling. Spoon out about 3-4 tablespoons depending on the size of your tortilla. Add some sriracha if that&rsquo;s your thing (and it should be). Wrap it up and enjoy!
</section></p>

<p>For good measure, I have a small cup of strawberries and pomegranate on the side. Strawberries and pomegranates make me happy.</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t expecting to have so much in the way of leftovers after making this yesterday, but it turns out to produce about 3-4 servings which is amazing. Leftovers win.</p>

<p>If I had some tahini lying around I may have swapped it out with the mayo for a vegan option. I also may experiment with using greek yogurt instead of mayo, but that may be an experiment for when I&rsquo;m slightly more daring.</p>

<p>Hopefully from here forward my photo quality will improve. Live and learn.</p>

<p>Oh and PS I made a perfect soft boiled egg for the first time today. Nothing photo-worthy as it was just more leftovers, but I&rsquo;ll definitely be making it again so stay tuned for that one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
